# Megan Matanda

## Full Stack Developer

- France
- 33643523557
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/megan-mat/
- https://github.com/Megan74

- ™ matandamegan@gmail.com
- Driving License
- https://twitter.com/TechieMeggy
- https://curious-starship-5689e7.netlify.app



#### **Profile**

Hi, I am Megan. I specialise as a full stack developer, I have mastered fundamental knowledge of modern frontend and backend technologies, by building web applications including the JavaScript, HTML, CSS, JSX programming languages, with Node.js and API tools, and related libraries/frameworks like Vue.js.

I describe myself as a passionate and curious self-starter who finds true enjoyment optimising user experiences, and supporting the delivery of impactful, well-performing projects around the world.

#### **Professional Experience**

12/2021 - present

#### Software engineer, 100Devs

**United-States** 

An American NGO that funded an inclusive online bi-weekly cohorts: for building impactful full stack projects, with Express.js Vue.js React and other famous frameworks, using, JavaScript HTML CSS3 programming languages. Also working on backend projects with Mongodb as a database platform.

06/2019 - present

#### Office Administrative Assistant, Crédit Agricole next bank

Geneva, Switzerland

- Reviewed external penetration tests and regulatory audits to remediate its findings to ensure the security of the network resources;
- Performed daily administrative functions such as answering calls and emails, scheduling meetings, writing multiple reports and other forms.
- Provided constant and reliable administrative support to 14 banking offices across Switzerland.
- Assisted the HR manager by maintaining personnel files for active and terminated employees.
- Maintained, coordinated and updated multiple databases, records and mailing lists.
- Maintained an inventory of office supplies.
- Transformed manual processes into a computerized, well-documented standard operating procedures system (SOP).
- Managed and prepared multiple reports, spreadsheets, documents and other forms and handled all media and PR inquiries.
- Scheduled meetings and managed the calendar, took the meeting minutes and forwarded the minutes via email to all the partners.

Skills

11/2016 - 12/2018

Flight Cabin Crew,, Etihad Airways, Royal Jet

Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates

#### CSS

(core technology for building Web pages)

### Github, Glitch, Codepen, VSCode

(platform that enables the rapid development and deployment of back-end applications like APIs, integrations and automations.)

#### React

A User Interface library on JavaScript language(JSX). I chose to work with that tool because it builds quickly and easily complex UI components.

#### **AWS**

Cloud computing solutions/ Application host

#### Javascript

(core technology for building Web pages)

#### **REST API**

lightweight data-interchange interface set with complex functionnalities

#### Express.js

I use that infrastructure to build APIS on the backend server.

#### Jest & Mocha

Code testing frameworks

#### Node.Js

Open source development platform for executing JavaScript code server-side with back end technologies.
My everyday tool to build my full stack projects.

#### Git

version control system that lets you manage and keep track of your source code history.

#### Nextjs

Bootstrap & Tailwind CSS frameworks

#### HTML5

(core technology for building Web pages)

#### Vue.js

Progressive framework to build front-end applications. I built my dog app with that tool, that I am very familiar with.

#### Mongodb

Data developer platform

#### Education

09/2012 - 06/2015 Law undergraduate courses -, Jean Moulin Lyon III University

Completed 35 credits towards a degree of laws

#### Certificates

#### Front-end Foxes bootcamp

Front-end web development skills Bootcamp

Technologies used:

CSS - HTML5 - Javascript - API

Software Engineering Virtual Experience Certificate of Completion 2

JP Morgan Virtual Experience Program - May 2022

Participated in the open access JP Morgan Virtual Experience Program

Tasks Completed include:

Technologies used: Python, NPM, Node.js

#### Courses

Udemy Javascript courses,

The Web Developer Bootcamp 2022 by Colt SteeleUdemy ☑

present JavaScript30 🛮

30 days Javascript project challenges

#100devs, NGO 🛮 Boston, United States present

Full stack development cohort funded by a non governmental organisation

Front-end foxes

Front-end web development skills Bootcamp

#### **Projects**

present Blog, Currently building and updating a blog that Shows my journey into tech and my hobbies

Using React Nextjs MDX tailwind

https://github.com/Megan74/myblog

CRUD Application with MERN stack: backend and frontend interface

A Mongo Express React Node stack application, using crud http methods, to submit client-side forms to the server, through Node and Express. Forms which will be then stored, updated/deleted, in the mongo database. https://github.com/Megan74/crud\_app/ 🛭

Dogstagram app 🛮

Like and store your favourite dog pictures.

technologies used: Javascript- CSS3 - API - Vue.js

https://github.com/Megan74/Dogstagram ☑

Todo list app ☑

Create lists and write off the things you have done.

Typing game 🛮

Fun game built with HTML, CSS and Javascript.

#### Languages

French • English

#### **Interests**

Fashion (I love designing clothes on Adobe Sketch, and then create it with fabrics with my sewing machine.), Sport (Running 10km twice a week, yoga, pilates, exercises indoor, hiking, snowshoeing and snowboarding), Travelling (Malaysia, Hong Kong, USA, China, Thailand, Japan, Costa Rica, Australia, Europe, Middle East)

Lyon

with Forage.

- Interface with a stock price data feed
- Use JPMorgan Chase frameworks and tools
- Display data visually for traders